<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<table version="1.000000" name="planetSpecs" numRows="13" numCols="4" flags="0" tableType="0">
    <rows>
        <row id="0" name=""/>
        <row id="1" name=""/>
        <row id="2" name=""/>
        <row id="3" name=""/>
        <row id="4" name=""/>
        <row id="5" name=""/>
        <row id="6" name=""/>
        <row id="7" name=""/>
        <row id="8" name=""/>
        <row id="9" name=""/>
        <row id="10" name=""/>
        <row id="11" name=""/>
        <row id="12" name=""/>
    </rows>
    <columns>
        <column id="0" name="HeaderText" type="1" readonly="1">Galactic Year\nDay\nMass\n\nRadius\n\nGravity\nSurface Temp\nMoons\nComposition,Orbital Period\nDay\nMass\n\nRadius\n\nGravity\nSurface Temp\nMoons\nAtmosphere,Orbital Period\nDay\nMass\n\nRadius\n\nGravity\nSurface Temp\nMoons\nComposition,Orbital Period\nDay\nMass\n\nRadius\n\nGravity\nSurface Temp\nMoons\nComposition,Orbital Period\nDay\nMass\n\nRadius\n\nGravity\nSurface Temp\nMoons\nAtmosphere,Orbital Period\nDay\nMass\n\nRadius\n\nGravity\nSurface Temp\nMoons\nComposition,Orbital Period\nDay\nMass\n\nRadius\n\nGravity\nSurface Temp\nMoons\nComposition,Orbital Period\nDay\nMass\n\nRadius\n\nGravity\nSurface Temp\nMoons\nComposition,Orbital Period\nDay\nMass\n\nRadius\n\nGravity\nSurface Temp\nMoons\nComposition,Orbital Period\nDay\nMass\n\nRadius\n\nGravity\nSurface Temp\nMoons\nComposition,Lunar Month\nLunar Day\nMass\n\nRadius\n\nGravity\nSurface Temp\nMoons\nComposition,,</column>
        <column id="1" name="DataText" type="1" readonly="0">225 million years\n24.47 days\n1.9891×10³⁰ kg\n333\,000 Earths\n696\,342 km\n109 Earths\n27.94 g \n5504°C\n0\nHydrogen 73.46%\nHelium 24.85 %\nOther 1.69%,87.969 days\n58.646 days\n3.3022×10²³ kg\n0.055 Earths\n2439.7±1.0 km\n0.3829 Earths\n0.38 g\n−193.15°C ~ 426.85°C\n0\nMolecular Oxygen 42%\nSodium 29.0%\nHydrogen 22.0%\nHelium 6.0%\nPotassium 0.5%\nOther 0.5%,224.701 days\n−243.0185 days\n4.8676×10²⁴ kg\n0.815 Earths\n6051.8±1.0 km\n0.9499 Earths\n0.904 g\n462°C\n27\nCarbon Dioxide ≈96.5%\nNitrogen ≈3.5%\nSulfur Dioxide 0.015%\nArgon 0.007%\nWater Vapour 0.002%\nCarbon Monoxide 0.0017%\nOther ≈0.0020%,365.2563 days\n23h 56m 4s\n5.97219×10²⁴ kg\n3.0×10⁻⁶ Suns\n6378.1 km\n1 Earth\n0.99732 g \n-88°C ~ 54°C\n1\nNitrogen 78.08%\nOxygen   20.95%\nArgon    0.93%\nOther\t 0.04%,686.971 days\n24h 37m 22s\n5.97219×10²⁴ kg\n3.0×10⁻⁶ Suns\n3\,376.2±0.1 km\n0.531 Earths\n0.376 g\n−143°C ~ 35°C\n2\nCarbon Dioxide 95.97%\nArgon 1.93%\nNitrogen 1.89%\nOther 0.21%,11.8618 years\n9h 55m 30s\n5.97219×10²⁴ kg\n3.0×10⁻⁶ Suns\n71492±4 km\n11.209 Earths\n2.528 g\n-108.15°C\n67\nHydrogen 89.8±2.0%\nHelium 10.2±2.0%\nMethane ≈ 0.3%\nAmmonia ≈ 0.026%\nOther ≈ 0.004%,29.4571 years\n10h 34m\n5.6846×10²⁶ kg\n95.152 Earths\n60268±4 km\n9.4492 Earths\n1.065 g\n-139°C\n62\nHydrogen ≈96%\nHelium ≈3%\nMethane ≈0.4%\nAmmonia ≈0.01%\nOther ≈0.01%,84.323326 years\n17h 14m 24s\n(8.6810±0.0013)×10²⁵ kg\n14.536 Earths\n25559±4 km\n4.007 Earths\n0.886 g\n−197.2°C\n27\nHydrogen 83±3%\nHelium 15±3%\nMethane 2.3%\nOther ≈2.7%,164.79 years\n16h 6min 36s\n1.0243×10²⁶\n17.147 Earths\n24764±15 km\n3.883 Earths\n1.14 g\n−201°C\n14\nHydrogen 80±3.2%\nHelium 19±3.2%\nMethane 1.5±0.5%\nHydrogen Deuteride ~0.019%\nEthane ~0.00015%,247.68 years\n6d 9h 17m 36s\n(1.305±0.007)×10²² kg\n0.00218 Earths\n1153±10 km\n0.18 Earths\n0.067 g\n−229°C\n5\nNitrogen\nMethane\nCarbon Monoxide,29.53059 days\n27.321661 days\n7.3477×1022 kg\n0.012300 Earths\t\t\t\t\n1738.14 km\n0.273 Earths\n0.1654 g\t\t\n-173.15 ~ 116.85\n0\nArgon\nHelium\nSodium\nPotassium\nHydrogen\nRadon,,</column>
        <column id="2" name="Item" type="1" readonly="0">Sun,Mercury,Venus,Earth,Mars,Jupiter,Saturn,Uranus,Neptune,Pluto,Moon,Phobos,Deimos</column>
        <column id="3" name="Blurb" type="1" readonly="0">The Sun is the star at the centre of our Solar System. The distance from the Sun to the Earth is known as an astronomical unit (AU) and is approximately 150 million kilometers. AU is used to measure distances across our Solar System. It is almost perfectly spherical and consists of hot plasma interwoven magnetic fields. The Sun formed about 4.57 billion years ago from gravitational collapse of a region of a molecular cloud. The sun is about ¾ Hydrogen\, while the rest is mostly Helium. The remainder (approximately 1.69%) consists of heavier elements\, including Oxygen\, Carbon\, Neon and Iron\, among others. In its core\, the Sun fuses about 620 million metric tons of Hydrogen each second.,Known about since ancient Romand and Greek Times\, Mercury is the closest planet to the Sun and is gravitationally locked making it unique in the Solar System. It rotates exactly 3 times for every 2 orbital periods. With an atmosphere being constantly blown away\, Mercury is a barren wasteland much like the surface of the moon with extreme temperatures between day and night. It is theorised that Mercury might have ice at it&apos;s polar caps in craters that are deep enough. Having the smallest axle tilt of 1/30 of a degree\, Mercury does not experience seasons like other planets do. Mercury&apos;s core has a higher iron content than that of any other major planet in the Solar System.,The second brightest object in the night sky\, Venus is sometimes referred to as Earth&apos;s &quot;sister planet&quot; because of their similar size\, gravity\, and bulk composition. It has the densest atmosphere of the four terrestrial planets\, consisting of more than 96% carbon dioxide. The atmospheric pressure at the planet&apos;s surface is 92 times that of Earth&apos;s. Venus rotates on it&apos;s axis in retrograde\, so the Sun rises in the West and sets in the East. The Soviet Venera 3 probe crash-landed on Venus on 1 March 1966 and was the first visit to this hostile world. The surface is ever changing as Venus is very volcanically active constantly changing the land.,Earth has the largest moon respective to the planet&apos;s size. A molten core of iron produces a magnetic field that protects Earth&apos;s atmosphere otherwise the solar winds would strip it away over time and life wouldn&apos;t be able to on our planet. Life appeared on the surface within 1 billion years of forming. The planet is home to millions of species of life\, including humans. Both the mineral resources of the planet and the products of the biosphere contribute resources that are used to support a global human population. Estimates on how much longer the planet will be able to continue to support life range from 500 million years\, up to 2.3 billion years.,Roughly half the size of Earth\, Mars is a terrestrial planet with a thin atmosphere. Mars Science Laboratory is a rover that will assess whether Mars ever was\, or is still today\, an environment able to support microbial life. Its mission is to determine the planet&apos;s &quot;habitability.&quot; Olympic Mons (Mount Olympus)\, is the tallest or second tallest mountain in the Solar System\, depending on how it is measured. Measurements range it from 21 to 27 km high. Mars has 2 small moons\, Phobos and Deimos. Evidence suggests that the planet was once significantly more habitable than it is today\, but whether living organisms ever existed there remains unknown.,Jupiter is the largest planet in our Solar System. Jupiter&apos;s mass is 2.5 times that of all the other planets in the Solar System combined\, yet is less dense than Earth. It has 67 natural moons\, 4 which are referred to as Galilean moons (discovered in Jan 1610 by Galileo). Well known for it&apos;s Great Red Spot\, a great anti-cyclonic (high pressure) storm akin to a hurricane on Earth\, but it is enormous (three Earths would fit within its boundaries) and it has persisted for at least the 400 years that humans have observed it through telescopes. Having no physical surface\, you would fall into the planet and eventually be crushed by pressure. It is theorised to have a core of liquid metallic Hydrogen.,Saturn is the sixth planet from the Sun and the second largest planet in the Solar System\, after Jupiter. Named after the Roman god of agriculture\, its astronomical symbol (♄) is a representation of the god&apos;s sickle. Saturn is a gas giant with an average radius about nine times that of Earth. Predominantly composed of gas\, it lacks a definite surface\, although it may have a solid core. Saturn&apos;s rings were not known to exist until Galileo first saw them in 1610. They consist of countless particles\, ranging from micrometers to metres. The ring particles are made almost entirely of water ice\, with a trace component of rocky material.,Uranus is similar in composition to Neptune\, of different chemical composition than the larger gas giants Jupiter and Saturn. For this reason\, astronomers sometimes place them in a separate category called &quot;ice giants&quot;. Uranus is flipped on it&apos;s side ≈97.9° and its north and south poles are where most other planets have their equator. It is the coldest planet in the Solar System and has 21 year seasonal changes. The rings are composed of extremely dark particles\, which vary in size from micrometers to a fraction of a meter. They did not form with Uranus and might be a moon that shattered by high-speed impacts. Uranus has 27 known moons. The names for these come from characters in the works of Shakespeare and Alexander Pope.,Neptune was the first planet found by mathematical prediction rather than by empirical observation.  Alexis Bouvard applied Newton&apos;s Laws of Gravity to the orbit of Uranus to deduce Neptune&apos;s existence. Neptune has been visited by one spacecraft\, Voyager 2\, which flew by the planet on 25 August 1989. Neptune&apos;s orbit has a profound impact on the region directly beyond it\, known as the Kuiper belt. The internal structure of Neptune consists of 4 main zones. The upper atmosphere consisting of the top clouds. An atmosphere consisting of hydrogen\, helium and methane gas. Mantle consisting of water\, ammonia and methane ices. The core consists of rock (silicates and nickel–iron).,Pluto (minor-planet designation 134340 Pluto) is the largest object in the Kuiper belt\, and the tenth-most-massive body observed directly orbiting the Sun. It is the second-most-massive known dwarf planet\, after Eris. Discovered in 1930\, Pluto was originally classified as the ninth planet from the Sun. Eris is 27% more massive than Pluto. The understanding that Pluto is only one of several large icy bodies in the outer Solar System prompted the International Astronomical Union (IAU) to formally define what it means to be a &quot;planet&quot; in 2006. This definition excluded Pluto and reclassified it as a member of the new &quot;dwarf planet&quot; category (and specifically as a plutoid).,The Moon is the only natural satellite of the Earth and the fifth largest moon in the Solar System. It is the most luminous object in the sky after the Sun. Although it appears a very bright white\, its surface is actually dark. After the Apollo 17 mission in 1972\, the Moon has been visited by only unmanned spacecraft. The Moon is under the Outer Space Treaty\, free to all nations to explore for peaceful purposes. The Moon is thought to have formed nearly 4.5 billion years ago\, not long after Earth. The tides on Earth are mostly generated the Moon&apos;s gravitational pull from one side of Earth to the other\, the tidal forces.,Phobos is the larger and closer of the two natural satellites of Mars. Both moons were discovered in 1877. A small\, irregularly shaped object with a mean radius of 11 km. Phobos orbits 6\,000 km from the Martian surface\, closer to its primary than any other known planetary moon. It is so close that it orbits Mars faster than Mars rotates. As a result\, from the surface of Mars it appears to rise in the west\, move across the sky in 4 hours 15 min or less\, and set in the east\, twice each Martian day. Due to tidal interactions\, Phobos is drawing closer to Mars by one meter every century\, and it is predicted that in 50 million years it will collide with the planet or break up into a planetary ring.,Deimos is the smaller and outermore of the two natural satellites of the planet Mars with a mean radius of 6.2 km. Deimos takes 30.3 hours to orbit Mars. Deimos&apos;s orbit is nearly circular and is close to Mars&apos;s equatorial plane. Deimos is possibly an asteroid that was perturbed by Jupiter into an orbit that allowed it to be captured by Mars\, though this hypothesis is still controversial and disputed. Deimos regularly passes in front of the Sun as seen from Mars. It is too small to cause a total eclipse\, appearing only as a small black dot moving across the Sun.</column>
    </columns>
</table>
